

Mahfuj Ahmed Jim

Software Engineer

Fresh Graduate with over 2 years of working experience. I am seeking an opportunity in a dynamic firm that values my analytical and technical skills. I am eager to contribute to the company's development while constantly upgrading my knowledge and advancing my personal growth.

mahfuj.jim2@gmail.com

87, North Bashabo, Dhaka-1214

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mahfuj-ahmed-jim-108771204

+880 1789 775266



https://github.com/mahfuj-ahmed-jim



f https://www.facebook.com/mahfuj.ahmed.jim.7712

TECHNICAL & SOFT SKILLS

- Technical Skills: Java | Dart | Android Studio | Flutter | Room | Hive | SQLite | Retrofit | Riverpod | Firebase
- Soft Skills: Time Management | Communication | Leadership | Problem Solving | Teamwork | Work Ethic

ACHIEVEMENT

Champion at Innovation Challenge Season 12 (Fall 22) □

• The event took place every semester where students has to showcase their Senior Design Project (Capstone). We got the award for Best Poster Design.

Champion at Intra NSU ACM SC Hackathon (2020)

Interpret an esoteric programming language. Developed a Graphical User Interface using Java Swing and save required information using Java File Class.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer (Contractual Project)

March, 2023 to Present (2 Months+)

Intasl Shipping Limited

- Developed UI designs for both mobile and web applications.
- Creating comprehensive documentations and diagrams for the projects.
- Utilizing Flutter for mobile application development with proper architecture and design pattern.

Software Engineer (Part Time)

September, 2022 to Present (8 Months+)

Daktar Lagbe Limited

- Develop Software within deadlines in the team and individual settings.
- Execute Software Development Life Cycle, create Diagrams and Documentations.
- Designing and developing advanced applications using Flutter and API Integration.

Mobile App Developer

August, 2021 to August, 2022 (1 Year)

Accelerating Intelligence

- Develop advanced Mobile Applications with external data and API Integration.
- Implement strategic engineering procedures for enhanced application performance.
- Continuously evaluate and implement new features to minimize bugs.

PROJECTS

Food Ordering System with Real Time Tracking (Khaben Naki) ☑

- User friendly online food ordering platform.
- Build with Android Studio, Java, Bootstrap, Firebase, Laravel, and cPanel

Automated Parking System (Rakhbo Koi) [2]

- Software and IoT based system without any human interaction.
- Build with Android Studio, Raspberry Pi, Firebase.

Easy Splitting of Group Expense (Bill Splitter) □

- Allow users to track, manage and split the bill in a group of people.
- Build with Flutter, Riverpod, Hive, Node.js, cPanel.

Messaging Service (We Chat) □

- A cross platform instant messaging application.
- Build with Flutter, Riverpod, Hive, Firebase.

EDUCATION

BSc in Computer Science and Engineering

North South University

CGPA 3.31 out of 4.00

January, 2019 to December, 2022 (4 Years)

• **Courses:** Object-oriented programming, Data structures, and algorithms, Database systems, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Theory of computation, Software Engineering, Junior Design, Senior Design.

Higher Secondary School Certificate

2018

National Ideal Collage

GPA 5.00 out of 5.00

Higher Secondary School Certificate

2016

National Ideal School GPA 5.00 out of 5.00

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITY

In-Charge

11/2022 to 04/2022 **(6 Months)**

NSU ACM Student Chapter

Member

7/2019 to 04/2022 (1Year 9 Months)

NSU ACM SC Research & Development Team

REFERENCE

Mr. Instisar Tahmid Naheen

Lecturer

North South University

Email: intisar.naheen@northsouth.edu

Phone: +880 1675 577647

Abdullah Al Mamun

CEO

Accelerating Intelligence

Email: amamun860@gmail.com

Phone: +880 1924 775541